(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
The First Note
重大告知あり
Major Announcement Included
hololive AIRLINE
（鼻歌）
(Humming)
（笑い声）
(Chuckling)
よっこらせ、よっこらせ。
Heave-ho, heave-ho.
危険
赤色警告灯点滅時はドアを開けないこと
DANGER
Do not open door if red warning light is flashing
うわあああ！ おとととと！
Whoaaa! Whoops, whoops!
お客様！ 席にお戻りください！
Ma'am! Please return to your seat!
みんな待ってるから 行かないと！
Everyone is waiting, I have to go!
危ないですよ！
It's dangerous!
え？
Huh?
よいしょ！
Heave-ho!
ちょっと！
Wait!
うわあああああ！
Waaaaah!
踊らで！ 奏で！
Let's dance! And play!
はっしゃー！
Launch!
奏がやってきたー！
Kanade has arrived!
オーーラー！
All riiiight!
盛り上がってく準備は できてるよなー！
Are you all ready to get hyped up?!
君の声をきかせて
Let me hear your voice
さあ 冒険してみらい
Come on, let's explore the future
楽しいこと始めよう
Let's start something fun
遊びたい ぜたい ぜたい
I want to play, play, play
あばれ ジョイ ジョイ ジョイ
Go wild, joy, joy, joy
とびきりのベイベー
An extraordinary baby
ジョイ ジョイ ジョイ
Joy, joy, joy
ハッピーなピーポー
Happy people
弱気な自分に おさらば
Say goodbye to your timid self
自信ありげに ピースサイン
Give a confident peace sign
君の瞳にキスをして
Kissing your eyes
笑いたい ぜたい ぜたい
I want to laugh, laugh, laugh
あばれ ジョイ ジョイ ジョイ
Go wild, joy, joy, joy
勇気のベイベー
A baby with courage
ジョイ ジョイ ジョイ
Joy, joy, joy
ハッピーなセイヤー
Happy sayers
君の心も染まった ドゥドゥ
Your heart is also dyed, doo-doo
僕の心も染まった イットゥトゥ
My heart is also dyed, it-too-too
はじけてるんじゃない
Aren't we bursting with energy
イッツ ジョイフル パピプペポパブー
It's joyful, pa-pi-pu-pe-po-pa-boo
ジョイ ジョイ ジョイ
Joy, joy, joy
とびきりのベイベー
An extraordinary baby
ジョイ ジョイ ジョイ
Joy, joy, joy
ハッピーなピーポー
Happy people
ドキドキしちゃうの 何でだろう
I wonder why my heart is pounding
ソワソワしちゃうの 何でだろう
I wonder why I'm feeling restless
この指にとまるのは
What alights on this finger
どんな運命なんだ 全部知りたいな
Is whatever fate? I want to know everything
いつだって終わっちゃう
Everything always comes to an end
エブリバディ いつか終わっちゃう
Everybody, it'll end someday
いついつも この時を
Always and forever, this moment
最終形はきっと 修正なしでいこう
The final form will surely be without edits
ウィドゥ ウィドゥ ウィダッドゥトゥ
We do, we do, we dad-doo-too
パピプペポパピプペポ
Pa-pi-pu-pe-po-pa-pi-pu-pe-po
笑いたい ぜたい ぜたい
I want to laugh, laugh, laugh
あばれ ジョイ ジョイ ジョイ
Go wild, joy, joy, joy
勇気のベイベー
A baby with courage
ジョイ ジョイ ジョイ
Joy, joy, joy
ハッピーなセイヤー
Happy sayers
君の心も染まった ドゥドゥ
Your heart is also dyed, doo-doo
僕の心も染まった イットゥトゥ
My heart is also dyed, it-too-too
はじけてるんじゃない
Aren't we bursting with energy
イッツ ジョイフル パピプペポパブー ジョイ！
It's joyful, pa-pi-pu-pe-po-pa-boo, joy!
ジョイ！
Joy!
ジョーーーイ！
Joyyyyy!
あれ？
Huh?
降ろして...
Let me down...
降ろせやー！
Let me down!
降ろしてー！ ああー！
Let me down! Ahhh!
え？
Huh?
いいから降ろせやー！
Just let me down already!
あああああーーー！
Aaaaahhh!
はい！ ということで始まりました！
Yes! And so, we have begun!
音乃瀬奏生誕祭2025！
Otonose Kanade Birthday Festival 2025!
いぇーーい！
Yay!
イェーイ！
いやもう大変だったわ、飛行機乗ってここまで来るのにさ。
Wow, it was quite a struggle, getting all the way here by plane.
ふーっ、疲れた。もう疲れたわ、私。
Phew, I'm exhausted. I'm already wiped out.
まって、とりあえず一応ハーネス取ってくるから、みんな待っててね！
Hold on, I'm gonna go take off this harness for now, so everyone please wait!
えい、見ないで！えい、えい...
Hey, don't look! Hup, hup...
はーい！
Hi there!
なったなった！
I did it, I did it!
えー、こちら音乃瀬奏生誕祭2025、ハッシュタグは...
Uh, so this is the Otonose Kanade Birthday Celebration 2025, and the hashtag is...
同じです！あ、こっちに書いてある。こっちに書いてある通り...
The same! Oh, it's written over here. Just like it says here...
え、音乃瀬奏生誕祭2025でいっぱいポストしてください！
Um, please post lots with #OtonoseKanadeBirthdayCelebration2025!
お願いします！
Please do!
そして今回は3Dになって初めてのお誕生日なので...
And since this is my first birthday after getting my 3D model...
いろんな音乃瀬奏を皆さんに見てもらえたらなと思っています！
I hope to show everyone many different sides of Kanade!
そして最後には重大告知あり！
And there's a major announcement at the end!
よかったら最後まで見てください！
So please watch until the very end!
なんだなんだなんだなんだ...
What's this, what's this, what's this...
すごいコメントがもうすごい速度。
The comments are coming in at an incredible speed.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
そしてゲストパートは一部収録です。
And the guest parts are partially pre-recorded.
生で歌ったり、えー、ダンスしたりもするので、よかったら見守ってください。
We'll also be singing and dancing live, so please keep an eye on us.
すごい草がいっぱいある。ありがとう！
Wow, there's so much "grass" (lol). Thank you!
奏ちゃん！
Kanade-chan!
お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy Birthday!
おーー！
Whoa--!
誰？誰？
Who is it? Who is it?
誰だったかな？忘れちゃった。ReGLOSSのバイブスの人たちだ！
Who was it? I forgot. It's the ReGLOSS vibe-checkers!
え、来てくれたの？
Wait, you guys came?
もちろん！
Of course!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
そっち行くから待っててね！
I'm coming over there, so wait for me!
来てくれるんだ！ありがとう！
She's coming over! Thank you!
やば、うちらも先にここ占拠しちゃってる。いいのかな。
Whoops, we've already taken over this spot. Is that okay?
占拠なの？これ占拠してるの？三人で。もう今ジャックしたぜ。
Takeover? Are we taking it over? The three of us. We've hijacked it now.
社長、社長、あ、落ちた...
Shacho, Shacho, ah, I fell...
そろそろ準備できたんじゃない？
Everything should be ready now, right?
え、もしかして歌うのか？え、歌うし踊るよ！
Wait, are we singing? Yeah, we're singing and dancing!
歌うの？やるよ！
Singing? Let's do it!
来るか？来るか？何が来るんだ？
Is it coming? Is it coming? What's coming?
繋がっていたいって信じられる言葉 だってもう昨日の僕らにおさらば",
Words I can believe in, wanting to stay connected, because we've already said goodbye to who we were yesterday
青い春を過ごした遠い稲妻
The distant lightning of the blue spring days we spent
ずっと泣いて前だけを向けたら きっとどんなに楽になれていただろうな
If only I could have kept crying while looking straight ahead, I wonder how much easier it would have been
この心を揺らした一縷の望みは
The sliver of hope that shook this heart is...
ないものねだりはやめた 未完成人間 素晴らしき世界だけが
I've stopped wishing for what I don't have, an incomplete human, only this wonderful world...
答えを握ってる
Holds the answer
諦めてしまうほどこの先たくさんの後悔が君を待ってるけど
Though so many regrets await you ahead that you might feel like giving up...
もう迷いはしないよ この傷も愛おしく思えてしまうほど
I won't hesitate anymore, to the point where even these wounds start to feel precious
重ねてしまうよ 不恰好なままでいいから 走れ その歩幅で
I'll keep layering them on, it's fine to be clumsy, just run, at your own pace
走れ 鼓動 鳴らしてくれ
Run, let your heart beat
歌いたいと舞うは 同じくらい抱きしめて
Dancing with the desire to sing, embrace it just as much
刻んだ今を 繋ぐ未来を目指して
Aiming for the future that connects to the moment we've carved
顔も名前も知らない僕たちが たった一つの音を書き鳴らす
We, who don't know each other's faces or names, strike a single note together
いたずらみたいな奇跡のような刹那
A moment like a prank, like a miracle
あっという間に流れる時がありのままであり続けられる怖さが
The fear that while time flows by in the blink of an eye, you can stay as you are
失った時間は取り戻せないけれど
The time lost cannot be regained, but...
過去を振り返ってばかりじゃ 泣いたっていいんだ
Don't just look back at the past, it's okay to cry
悔しさと痛みだけが 君を肯定するから
Because only frustration and pain will validate you
大人になったら忘れてしまうの 君と約束をした場所は
Will you forget once you've grown up? The place where I made a promise with you
もう思い出したいよ 思い出も愛おしく思えてしまうほど
I want to remember it now, to the point where even the memories feel precious
踊る 重なってしまうよ
Dancing, we overlap
不恰好なままでいいから
It's okay to be clumsy
その声は どこまでも鳴り響いて
That voice will resonate forever
確かな理由を抱いて
Holding a certain reason
ここまで来たんだ ああ
I've come this far, ah
まだ終わらない 旅路なんだ
The journey hasn't ended yet
いつか 思いは形になる
Someday, feelings will take shape
この真っ白に染まる朝
This morning dyed in pure white
忘れられないままの宝
A treasure that remains unforgettable
諦めてしまうほど この先たくさんの
So much that I might give up, ahead lie many...
もうない 迷いはしないよ
No more, I won't hesitate anymore
かけがえのないもの 溢れてしまうよ
Irreplaceable things are overflowing
答えは君のその手の中に
The answer is in your hands
離さないで 物語は一歩前
Don't let go, the story takes a step forward
諦めてしまうほど
So much that I might give up
この先たくさんの 後悔が君を待ってる
Many regrets are waiting for you ahead
けどもうない 迷いはしないよ
But no more, I won't hesitate anymore
この傷も愛おしく思えてしまうほど
So much that even these wounds seem dear
重なってしまうよ
We overlap
不恰好なままでいいから
It's okay to be clumsy
走れ その歩幅で
Run, at your own pace
走れ 声を届かせてくれ
Run, let your voice be heard
期待と不安を同じくらい抱きしめて
Embrace expectation and anxiety in equal measure
澄んだ今を紡ぐ未来 照らして
Illuminate the future spun from this clear present
ありがとー！ おめでとー！
Thank you! Congratulations!
改めておめでとー！ ありがとー！
Congratulations again! Thank you!
待って、そういえば自己紹介してなくね？ あー、確かに。誰ですか？
Wait, come to think of it, we haven't introduced ourselves? Oh, true. Who are you guys?
はい！えー、可愛いポジティブジーニアス、奏の女、一条莉々華です！
Yes! Um, the cute positive genius, Kanade's woman, Ichijou Ririka here!
奏の女！ ふぅー！
Kanade's woman! Woo!
ブンブンバー！轟はじめ、えー、奏のお姉ちゃん、よろしこー！
Vroom vroom baa! Todoroki Hajime, um, Kanade's big sister, nice to meetcha!
お姉ちゃんだわ。お姉さんだわ。どう考えても。
She's the big sister. She's the big sister. No matter how you look at it.
はい！はい、えー、ReGLOSSの儒烏風亭らでんでございますー！えー、音乃瀬奏の、コーチ！
Yes! Yes, um, I'm ReGLOSS's Juufuutei Raden! Uh, Otonose Kanade's coach!
コーチ！？ 何を教えたの？ 教わった記憶ないんだけど。
Coach!? What did you teach her? I don't remember being taught anything.
見習え、奏を。見習え。こっちがコーチな。それ。
Learn from Kanade. Learn from her. I'm the coach here. That's it.
はい！ということで、ReGLOSSのみんな来てくれてありがとー！
Yes! So, ReGLOSS everyone, thank you for coming!
この曲歌いたかったんだー！ いい曲。めっちゃいい曲。
I really wanted to sing this song! It's a good song. A really good song.
次はゲストパートなんだけど、一緒にコールお願いしてもいいかな？
Next is the guest part, but could I ask you guys to do the call with me?
もちろん！ おー！
Of course! Oh!
じゃあ、行くよ。せーの、どうぞー！
Then, here we go. One, two, go!
何も考えなくていいよ 口ずさむばかり愛藍の
You don't have to think about anything, just humming my beloved indigo
この音に舞うのよ 忘れないでいたいよ ああ
Dancing to this sound, I want to keep it in my memory, ah
体は無彩色 レイドバック ただうねる音でグルーヴ
The body is achromatic, laid-back, just grooving with the undulating sound
ずっと二人で暮らそうよ この夜の隅っこで
Let's live together forever, in a corner of this night
目眩い僕らでいいよ 手を誘ったのは君じゃないの
Dizzy as we are is fine, it wasn't you who invited me by the hand
理屈だけじゃつまらないわ まだ時間が惜しいの おお
Just logic is boring, time is still precious, oh
練り歩く景色はシンコペ 踏み鳴らす足音でグルーヴ
The walking scenery is syncope, grooving with the sound of stomping footsteps
まるで僕らはブレーメン たった二人だけの街
It's as if we are Bremen, a town for just the two of us
さあ 息を吸って 吐いて 早く吐いて
Come on, take a breath, exhale, exhale quickly
焦って歌っていようぜ 笑う門に舞うもどだい
Let's keep singing in a hurry, dancing at the gate of laughter is the foundation
愛の歌 歌ってんのさ あははは
We're singing a song of love, ahahaha
焦って楽してこうぜ 死ぬほどのことはこの世にないぜ
Let's hurry and take it easy, there's nothing in this world worth dying for
...明日は何しようか
...what should we do tomorrow?
暇なら分かり合おうぜ
If we're free, let's understand each other.
ねぇ考えなくてもいいよ
Hey, you don't have to think about it.
踊り始めた君の細胞
Your cells have started to dance.
この音に今は乗ろうよ
Let's ride this sound for now.
乗れなくてもいいよ Oh
It's okay if you can't, oh.
思い出の景色でバックパック
Backpacking through landscapes of memories.
春風のざわめきでグルーヴ
Grooving with the rustle of the spring breeze.
もっと二人で歌おうよ
Let's sing more together.
暇なら愛をしようよ
If we're free, let's make love.
さぁ 息を吸って
Now, take a breath,
声に出して
and speak out.
Say Say 歌ってようぜ
Say say, let's keep singing.
笑われてるのも仕方がないね
It can't be helped if we're being laughed at.
何もかも間違ってんのさ
Everything is just wrong.
Say Say 楽していこうぜ
Say say, let's take it easy.
馬鹿よそう 泥沼じゃないぜ
Stop being a fool, it's not a quagmire.
同じような歌詞だし
The lyrics are similar, so
3番は飛ばしていいよ
you can skip the third verse.
さぁ 息を吸って
Now, take a breath,
早く吐いて
and quickly breathe out.
ねぇ 心を貸して
Hey, lend me your heart,
今日ぐらいは
at least for today.
Say Say 歌ってようぜ
Say say, let's keep singing.
違うか お前らみんな 僕のこと笑ってるのか
Or am I wrong? Are you all laughing at me?
Say Say 楽していこうぜ
Say say, let's take it easy.
死ぬほど辛い 悩みなどそうさ
That's right, worries that are painfully difficult...
数年も経てばきっと 一人も覚えてないよ
After a few years, surely no one will remember.
Say Say 歌ってようぜ
Say say, let's keep singing.
体は動く お前はどうだい
The body moves, how about you?
愛の歌歌ってんのさ
I'm singing a song of love.
Say Say 楽していこうぜ
Say say, let's take it easy.
死ぬほどのことなど この世にないぜ
There's nothing in this world worth dying for.
明日は何しようか
What should we do tomorrow?
暇なら笑い合おうぜ
If we're free, let's laugh together.
そのうち分かり合おうぜ
Let's understand each other soon.
奏 (かなで)
Kanade
改札の前 つなぐ手と手
In front of the ticket gate, holding hands.
いつものざわめき 新しい風
The usual bustle, a new breeze.
明るく見送るはずだったのに
I was supposed to see you off cheerfully, but...
うまく笑えずに 君を見ていた
I couldn't smile properly while looking at you.
君が大人になってく その季節が
The season when you become an adult,
悲しい歌で溢れないように
So that it won't be filled with sad songs,
最後に何か君に伝えたくて
I wanted to tell you something at the end,
「さよなら」に代わる言葉を僕は探してた
I was looking for words to replace "goodbye".
君の手を引く...
Pulling your hand...
その役目が僕を締め付けるなんて
That such a role would stifle me...
そう思ってた だけど今分かったんだ
I thought so, but now I understand,
僕らならもう
for us...
重ねた日々がほら 導いてくれる
See, the days we've shared together will guide us.
君が大人になって その時間が
As you grow into an adult, as that time...
降り積もる間に 僕も変わってく
...accumulates, I too will change.
例えばそこに こんな歌があれば
For instance, if there's a song like this there...
二人はいつも どんな時も
...the two of us can always, no matter when,
繋がっていける
...stay connected.
突然不意に 鳴り響くベルの音
Suddenly and unexpectedly, the bell rings.
焦る僕 解ける手 離れてく君
Me in a hurry, hands unclasping, you moving away.
夢中で呼び止めて 抱きしめたんだ
I called out frantically and held you tight.
君がどこに行ったって
No matter where you go,
僕の声で守るよ
I'll protect you with my voice.
君が僕の前に 現れた日から
From the day you appeared before me...
何もかもが 違って見えたんだ
...everything began to look different.
朝の光も 涙も 歌う声も
The morning light, the tears, and the singing voice...
君が輝きを くれたんだ
...you gave them all their radiance.
抑えきれない 思いをこの声に乗せて
I'll put these uncontrollable feelings into this voice...
遠く君の街へ 届けよう
...and let them reach your distant town.
例えばそれが こんな歌だったら
For instance, if it's a song like this...
僕らはどこに いたとしても
...we can stay connected,
繋がっていける
no matter where we are.
No title / 作詞・作曲：Reol
No title / Lyrics & Composition: Reol
ずっと夢見てた僕になれたかな
I wonder if I've become the person I always dreamed of.
とに帰れないとこまで来たみたい
It seems I've already reached a point of no return.
自分の足で二段飛ばして
Skipping two steps at a time with my own feet...
そのもっと先へ駆けて行けるはずだから
...I should be able to run even further.
Run away
深くなる傷を縫いつけ
Stitching up the wounds that grow deeper...
劇的に回り出す 慣れた痛み
...they dramatically start to spin, this familiar pain...
焦る呼吸をトビキリ
...this racing breath, extraordinary...
綺麗なふりして また
...pretending to be beautiful, once again.
何が正当？ 内乱エゴ 誰が間違った？ 曖昧なまま
What's right? Internal ego. Who was wrong? Remaining vague.
あんたが嫌いな あいつはきっとただそれだけで正解なんだ
That person you hate is surely right just for that reason.
0点だって提言したって 全然納得できない理由（わけ）は
Even if you declare it's a zero score, the reason I can't accept it at all is...
最前はいつだってここだった 最盛期は最初からなかった
...the front line was always here; there was no peak from the start.
緩やかに崩れ壊れていく
Slowly crumbling and breaking apart.
ゆるりゆるり首を絞めるより
Rather than slowly, slowly strangling me...
昨日までの僕が殺されていく
...the me of yesterday is being killed off.
緩やかに離れ離れになる
Slowly drifting apart.
クラリ君に聞こえるのは 僕が知らない声になって
Dizzily, what you hear becomes a voice unknown to me.
幼い頃から気づいたらそばにいた
Since I was young, I realized you were always by my side
まるで空気のようだ
Just like the very air I breathe
僕は君とギュッと手を繋いで
I held your hand tightly
楽しいことも涙も
The fun times and the tears
僕は君に話して聞かせた
I told you all about them
僕を笑う人やけなす声
The voices of those who laugh or mock me
かき消えるように
So they would be drowned out
この声を君が自身の体温と共鳴させてくれ
Let this voice resonate with your own body temperature
使い捨てだって言って腐っても
Even if they call it disposable and it rots
止まらないハイファイ　対等な期待
The unstoppable hi-fi, equal expectations
一瞬めぐる間の
In the span of a single moment
たった一瞬だけでも
Even if just for a single instant
交わる鼓動　音を繋ぐ色
Intersecting heartbeats, colors connecting sounds
次は僕が君に歌うんだ
Next, I'll be the one singing to you
緩やかに崩れ割れていく
Slowly crumbling and breaking apart
ゆるりゆるり首を絞めるより
Rather than slowly, slowly being strangled
昨日までの僕が殺されていく
The me until yesterday is being killed
緩やかに離ればなれを
Slowly, drifting apart
くらりんに君に聞こえるのは
In your daze, what you hear
僕が知らない声になって
Becomes a voice I don't know
緩やかに崩れ割れていく
Slowly crumbling and breaking apart
ゆるりゆるり首を絞めるより
Rather than slowly, slowly being strangled
昨日までの僕が殺されていく
The me until yesterday is being killed
緩やかに離ればなれを
Slowly, drifting apart
くらりんに君に聞こえるのは
In your daze, what you hear
僕が知らない声になって
Becomes a voice I don't know
いつか君に届くかな
I wonder if I'll reach you someday
いやそんな日はきっと来ないだろうな
No, such a day will surely never come
声も体もボロボロ君に救われた何億分の一
Voice and body tattered, one in hundreds of millions saved by you
形を合わせ彩った
The shapes fit together, colored
音で世界が溢れた
The world overflowed with sound
巡り巡り出会ったこの音を聞く
Listening to this sound we met by chance
すべてが
Everything
緩やかに崩れ割れていく
Slowly crumbling and breaking apart
ゆるりゆるり首を絞めるより
Rather than slowly, slowly being strangled
昨日までの僕が殺されていく
The me until yesterday is being killed
緩やかに離ればなれを
Slowly, drifting apart
くらりんに君に聞こえるのは
In your daze, what you hear
僕が知らない声になって
Becomes a voice I don't know
好き嫌い重視 I don't care what you think
Prioritizing likes and dislikes, I don't care what you think
掲げてこー　マジョリティ　あたしに負けはなし
Let's hold it high, the majority, I never lose
BANG!!!
作詞：ryo (supercell) 作曲：Giga
Lyrics: ryo (supercell) Music: Giga
ここまでって引かれたその境界線（ボーダー）だれのルール？
This boundary line drawn 'this far', whose rule is it?
案の定乗り越えたWe've got
As expected, we've crossed it, we've got
強く鳴った心笑い飛ばした　Get haha
Laughed off the heart that beat strongly, Get haha
言いたいことは言う
I say what I want to say
やりたくないことはしない
I don't do what I don't want to do
悪意気にしない　エナジー全開だわ
I don't care about malice, my energy is at full throttle
道無き道のそう前進だわ
Moving forward even on a pathless road
あたしも変わんない　ニューノーマルの時代
I won't change either, in this new normal era
Everybody say I want to be free
いつまでも思いを言わない　それじゃ何も変えられん
If you never speak your mind, you won't change anything
Everybody say I want life more
叶えて自分肯定　生きてるんだって
Grant yourself self-affirmation, you're alive
生きてるんだって
Saying I'm alive
ねぇ　生きてるんだって
Hey, I'm alive
歌え今
Sing it now
うたいま
Sing it out
Woah-oh-oh-oh
産声あげたその時から選ばれてきたんだ　思い出せ
We've been chosen from our first cry, remember that
あたしはあたしだ　不可能（不可）なことなんて
I am who I am, things like impossibilities...
何一つもないそうじゃない？　最高峰（ダイモン）に
...there isn't even one, right? To the highest peak
好き嫌い重視 I don't care what you think
Prioritizing likes and dislikes, I don't care what you think
フォルテ鳴らす
Sound the forte
このリリックかます
Deliver these lyrics
わからす挑発　下向いて舌打ちからの　はっ？
A clear provocation, a look down and a tongue click... hah?
Excuse me?
容赦せず倍返し　パンチライン　聞かせてあげるわ
Payback with no mercy, I'll show you a punchline
ヤケ火傷考えな
Think about the burns you'll get
あたしが憑いてるからな
Because I'm right here with you
Everybody say, I want to be free
揺らいだこのビート 苦笑 完全防備 黙る訴訟
This wavering beat, a bitter smile, fully guarded, a silent lawsuit
Everybody say, I want to like more
見せます A killa Wake up, wake up, いけてるんだ Dash
I'll show you, a killa, wake up wake up, it's a dash!
ねえ いけてるんだ Dash
Hey, it's a dash!
生まれたその時から 選ばれてきたんだ 名前まで
Since the moment I was born, I was chosen, even my name
私は私だ 不可能なことなど 何ひとつない そうじゃないの
I am who I am, nothing is impossible, isn't that right?
生まれたその時から 選ばれてきたんだ 名前まで
Since the moment I was born, I was chosen, even my name
あなたはあなただ 不可能なことなど 何ひとつない そうじゃないの
You are who you are, nothing is impossible, isn't that right?
なりたい自分に
To the person I want to be
好き嫌い 重視 気にしない I don't care ぶっ飛べ BANG!!!
Focus on likes and dislikes, I don't care, blast off, BANG!!!
ローリンガール / 作詞・作曲：wowaka
Rolling Girl / Lyrics & Music: wowaka
ローリンガールはいつまでも
The rolling girl, forever,
届かない夢見て
Dreaming unreachable dreams,
騒ぐ頭の中を
The inside of her noisy head
掻き回して、掻き回して
She stirs it up, stirs it up.
「もう一回。」と呟いて
Muttering, "One more time,"
言葉は失われた！
The words were lost!
もう失敗、もう失敗。
Another failure, another failure.
間違い探しに終われば、また、回るの！
Ending up searching for mistakes, I roll again!
もう一回、もう一回。
One more time, one more time.
「私は今日も転がります。」と、
"I'll roll again today," says
少女は言う 少女は言う
The girl, the girl says,
言葉に意味を奏でながら！
Playing the meaning into her words!
「もう一回？」
"One more time?"
「まだですよ、
"Not yet,
まだまだ先は見えないので。
Since the path ahead is still not visible.
息を止めるの、今。」
Holding my breath, now."
ローリンガールの成れの果て
The rolling girl's ruined end,
届かない向こうの色
The color beyond her reach,
重なる声と声を
The overlapping voices,
混ぜ合わせて、混ぜ合わせて
Mixing them, mixing them.
「問題ない。」と呟いた
Muttering, "No problem."
言葉は失われた。
The words were lost.
どうなったっていいんだってさ、
She said, "I don't care what happens,"
間違いだって起こしちゃおうと
Even if I'm making a mistake,
誘う、今。
Now, she beckons.
もう一回、もう一回。
One more time, one more time.
「私をどうか転がして。」と
"Please, roll me along," says
少女は言う 少女は言う
The girl, the girl says,
無口に意味を重ねながら！
Heaping meaning onto her silence!
「もう一回？」
"One more time?"
「あと少し。もうすぐ何か見えるだろう。」と
"Just a bit more. Soon I'll see something," as
息を止めるの、今。
Holding my breath, now.
もう一回、もう一回。
One more time, one more time.
「私は今日も転がります。」と、
"I'll roll again today," says
少女は言う 少女は言う
The girl, the girl says,
言葉に笑みを奏でながら！
Playing a smile into her words!
「もう一回？もういいよ。
"One more time? It's enough.
そろそろ君も疲れたろう、ね。」
You must be tired by now, right?"
息を止めるの、今。
Stopping my breath, now.
ベテルギウス / 作詞・作曲：優里
Betelgeuse / Lyrics & Music: Yuuri
空にある何かを見つめてたら
While I was staring at something in the sky
それは星だって君が教えてくれた
You told me that it was a star
まるでそれは僕らみたい
It's just like us
愛に寄り添ってる
Living close to love,
それを泣いたり笑ったり繋いでいく
Connecting it all through tears and laughter.
何十回何百回ぶつかりあって
Clashing tens, hundreds of times,
何十年何百年昔の光が
The light from tens, hundreds of years ago,
僕自身も忘れたころに
Just as I had forgotten about it,
僕らに届いてる
Has reached us.
僕ら見つめ合って 手繰り合って同じ空
Gazing at each other, drawing closer under the same sky,
輝くのだって二人だって約束した
We promised that we'd shine together, just the two of us.
遥か遠く終わらないベテルギウス
In the far distance, the never-ending Betelgeuse,
誰かに繋ぐ魔法
A magic that connects us to someone.
僕ら肩並べて 取り合って進んでく
Walking side-by-side, holding hands as we go,
辛い時だって泣かないって誓っただろ
We swore we wouldn't cry even in hard times, didn't we?
遥か遠く終わらないベテルギウス
In the far distance, the never-ending Betelgeuse,
君にも見えるだろう
You can see it too, can't you?
祈りが
Our prayer.
記憶を辿るたび 蘇るよ
Every time I trace my memories, it comes back to me,
君がいつだってそこにいてくれること
That you are always there for me.
まるでそれは星の光と同じように
It's just like the starlight,
今日を泣いたり笑ったり繋いでいく
Connecting today through tears and laughter.
何十回何百回ぶつかりあって
Clashing tens, hundreds of times,
何十年何百年昔の光が
The light from tens, hundreds of years ago,
僕自身も忘れたころに
Just as I had forgotten about it,
僕らの照らしてる
Is shining upon us.
僕ら見つめ合って 手繰り合って同じ空
Gazing at each other, drawing closer under the same sky,
輝くのだって二人だって約束した
We promised that we'd shine together, just the two of us.
遥か遠く終わらないベテルギウス
In the far distance, the never-ending Betelgeuse,
誰かに繋ぐ魔法
A magic that connects us to someone.
どこまでいつまで生きられるか
How far, and for how long can we live?
君が不安になるたびに強がるんだ
Every time you get anxious, I'll act tough.
大丈夫僕が横にいるよ
It's okay, I'm right here by your side.
見えない線を繋ごう
Let's connect an invisible line.
僕ら見つめ合って 手繰り合って同じ空
Gazing at each other, drawing closer under the same sky,
輝くのだって二人だって約束した
We promised that we'd shine together, just the two of us.
遥か遠く終わらないベテルギウス
In the far distance, the never-ending Betelgeuse,
誰かに繋ぐ魔法
A magic that connects us to someone.
僕ら肩並べて 取り合って進んでく
Walking side-by-side, holding hands as we go,
辛い時だって泣かないって誓っただろ
We swore we wouldn't cry even in hard times, didn't we?
遥か遠く終わらないベテルギウス
In the far distance, the never-ending Betelgeuse,
君にも見えるだろう
You can see it too, can't you?
祈りが
Our prayer.
空にある何かを見つめてたら
As I was gazing at something in the sky,
それは星だって君が教えてくれた
You told me that those were stars.
アカシア
Acacia
透明よりも綺麗なあの輝きを確かめに行こう
Let's go and witness that radiance, clearer than transparency.
そうやって始まったんだよ たまに忘れるほど強い理由
That's how it all started, with a reason so strong I sometimes forget it.
冷たい雨に濡れる時は足音比べ騒ぎながら行こう
When we get soaked in the cold rain, let's make some noise and compare our footsteps as we go.
太陽の代わりに歌を 君と僕と世界の声で
Let's sing instead of the sun, with your voice, mine, and the voice of the world.
いつか君を見つけた時に 君に僕も見つけてもらったんだな
The moment I found you, you found me too, didn't you?
今目が合えば笑うだけさ 言葉の外側で
Now if our eyes meet, we'll just laugh, beyond the realm of words.
ゴールはきっとまだだけど
The goal is surely still far off, but
もう死ぬまでいたい場所にいる
I'm already in the place where I want to stay until I die
隣で　君の側で
By your side, right next to you
魂がここだよと叫ぶ
My soul cries out that it's right here
泣いたり笑ったりする時
When we cry or laugh together
君の命が揺れる時
When your life trembles
誰より特等席で
In the best seat of all
僕も同じように息をしていたい
I want to be breathing just like you
Oh yeah, yeah, aha
君の一歩は僕より遠い
Your stride is longer than mine
間違いなく君の凄いところ
That's definitely one of your amazing points
足跡は僕の方が多い
But I've left more footprints behind
間違いなく僕の凄いところ
That's definitely one of my amazing points
真っ暗闇が怖い時は
When you're afraid of the pitch black darkness
怖さを比べ　ふざけながら行こう
Let's compare our fears and move on jokingly
太陽が無くたって歩ける
I can walk even without the sun
君と照らす世界が見える
I can see the world you light up
言えない事聞かないままで
Without asking about the things you can't say
消えない傷の意味知らないままで
Without knowing the meaning of your indelible scars
でも目が合えば笑えるのさ
But we can smile if our eyes meet
涙を挟んでも
Even with tears between us
転んだら手を貸してもらうよりも
Rather than having a hand lent when I fall
優しい言葉選んでもらうよりも
Rather than having kind words chosen for me
隣で信じて欲しいんだ
I want you to believe in me by my side
どこまでも一緒に行けると
That we can go anywhere together
ついに辿り着くその時
When we finally reach the destination
夢の正体に触れる時
When we touch the true form of our dreams
必ず一番側で
I'll surely be closest to you
君の目に映る景色にいたい
I want to be in the scenery reflected in your eyes
あの輝きを
That brilliance
君に会えたから見えた
I saw it because I met you
あの輝きを確かめに行こう
Let's go and confirm that brilliance
Oh yeah, yeah, aha
どんな最後が待っていようと
No matter what kind of end awaits
もう離せない手を繋いだよ
I've held your hand and won't let go
隣で　隣で　君の側で
By your side, right next to you
魂がここだよと叫ぶ
My soul cries out that it's right here
そして理由が光る時
And when the reason shines
僕らを理由が抱きしめる時
When the reason embraces us
誰より近くで特等席で
Closer than anyone, in the best seat
僕の見た君を君に伝えたい
I want to tell you about the you that I saw
君がいることを君に伝えたい
I want to tell you that you are here
そうやって始まったんだよ
That's how it all began
Oh yeah, yeah, aha
うわぁー！ママたちが来たぞー！
Whoa! The mamas are here!
ママたちー！奏ちゃーん！
Mamas! Kanade-chan!
お誕生日おめでとうー！
Happy birthday!
おめでとう！ありがとうございます！
Congratulations! Thank you very much!
おめでたい！おめでたい！
Happy birthday! Happy birthday!
おめでたいおめでたいおめでたいおめでたい...
Happy birthday, happy birthday, happy birthday...
騒がしいなあ。
So noisy.
お前に言われたくねーわ。
I don't want to hear that from you.
確かに！奏ちゃんが一番浮き浮きしてんじゃんねえ。
True! Kanade-chan is the most excited one.
だって、だって誕生日だから！
Because, because it's my birthday!
そうだよね！
That's true!
お母さんたち、産んでくれてありがとうございます！
Mamas, thank you for giving birth to me!
産んでは、産んではない！
I didn't, I didn't give birth!
産んではない！その誤解やめて！
I didn't give birth! Stop that misunderstanding!
こちらこそだよ！
Same here!
どこ産んでんねん。
Where did I give birth?
ど、どこも産んでません。
W-We didn't give birth to anything.
流石に、ママ、ママですけど産んでません。
We're mamas, but we didn't give birth.
はい！
Right!
そして今日は何話すんですか、ここから？
And what are we talking about today, from here?
そうですね、えっと、これまでのコラボの感想を...
Well, let's see, reflections on our collaborations so far...
めちゃめちゃある。
There are so many.
覚えきれてんのかな？
I wonder if she remembers them all?
大丈夫かな？
Is she okay?
ゆ、言うていい？
C-Can I say it?
じゃあ一番印象深かったの何？奏ちゃんが。
Then, what was the most memorable one for you, Kanade-chan?
気になる！
I'm curious!
でも言うて、このママたちでやったコラボって、実は一個しかないんです。
But to be honest, there's actually only one collaboration we've done as this 'mamas' group.
ああー！確かに！
Ah! True!
あ、そっかあ。
Oh, right.
あれ？でもそういえばなんか、赤い髪の毛の人...
Huh? But come to think of it, someone with red hair...
あれ？
Huh?
今日いない。
She's not here today.
やっぱりアレじゃない？産んだとか言うから...
Isn't it because she said she gave birth...?
あ、それだ。それでちょっと来られないのは...
Ah, that's it. That's why she couldn't come...
あ、でもなんか、スケジュール的に...
Oh, but like, due to scheduling...
あ、そうなんだ。
Oh, I see.
一応聞いてみたんですけど、ちょっと都合が合わず...
I did ask her, but unfortunately our schedules didn't line up...
あ、忙しい。
Ah, busy.
...いつかまたね、みんなで出来るといいね。
...Hopefully we can all do this together again someday.
そう、コラボとかもしたいね。
Yeah, I'd like to do collabs too.
ねー。
Yeah.
したい、したい！
I want to, I want to!
イエーイ！
Yay!
あの、ゲームコラボ以来だからね。
It's been since that game collab, right?
そうだねー。
That's right.
はい、えーっと...
Alright, well...
次、次、次、次、次やる？
Next, next, next, next, next one?
え、印象、印象、印象！
Wait, impressions, impressions, impressions!
おー、いいねー！
Oh, nice!
そうです、そうです。印象の変化とか言っていきます。
That's right. Let's talk about
how your impressions of me have changed.
えーと、まず、スバルまま。
Well, first, Subaru-mama.
あ、これスバルたちが言うんじゃないの？
Wait, aren't we the ones supposed to say it?
奏ちゃんに対しての印象でしょ？
You mean our impressions of you, Kanade-chan?
あ、そっちか！あーはいはいはい。
Oh, that's what you meant! Okay, okay.
え、じゃあ聞きたい、聞きたい。どっちから行く？
Oh, then I want to hear it. Who goes first?
どっちから行く？
Who goes first?
え、どっちにしようかな？じゃあ目ぇ瞑って...こっち！
Uhm, who should it be? Okay, close your eyes... this way!
あ、じゃあスバルちゃんから。
Ah, let's start with Subaru-chan.
もうこっちはスバルからだね。
Then I'll go first.
奏は最初は、はい。
Kanade, at first...
なんかARKで騒いでるの見て、
seeing you making a ruckus in ARK,
「なんだこいつ」と思って。
I thought, "Who's this kid?"
「なんだこいつ」！？
"Who's this kid"!?
でも、ARKであの、声がカッスカスしてるときから、
But even back then in ARK,
when your voice was all raspy,
ホロライブメンバーの中では、奏は大丈夫だなーって。
among the Hololive members, we thought,
"Kanade will be just fine."
「大丈夫だな」！？
"She'll be fine"!?
「こいつは大丈夫だ」っていう元気さがあったんですよ。
You had this liveliness that said,
"This kid's gonna be okay."
でもね、GTAで最後、奏ちゃんが...
But you know, at the end of GTA, Kanade-chan...
逮捕した...だ、もうその顔やめろお前！
...arrested... hey, stop making that face!
近いねん！
You're too close!
で、なんか逮捕したりとかね、そのあと奏ちゃん実はね、
Yeah, like after the arrest,
Kanade-chan actually...
「私もっと頑張りたいです」って、
"I want to work even harder,"
なんか電話してきたりとかね。
she actually called me and said.
え、それ言っちゃうの！？あー！
Wait, you're telling that story!? Ahh!
なんか、頑張り屋さんなんだなって思いました。
It made me think, she's a real hard worker.
おめでとう！誕生日おめでとう！
Congratulations! Happy birthday!
ありがとうございまーす！
Thank you so much!
さぁそして次は！
And now, next!
次は！ノエルまま。
Next up! Noel-mama.
はい、奏ちゃんはね、最初デビューしたときさ、
Yes, Kanade-chan, when she first debuted,
あ、歌もすごく上手くてね、
she was such a good singer,
団長とは別世界の人間なんだなと思って全然絡めなかったんだけど、
I thought she was from a different world
and couldn't really talk to her,
いやでもね、あの、マイクラで覚えたてのダイヤをね、
but you know, those diamonds
she just found in Minecraft,
団長から、あの、嘘ついてね、盗ったりとか。
she lied to me and stole them.
そっから、「あ、この子はそういう子なんだ」って。
From then on, I was like,
"Oh, so she's that kind of kid."
あ、結構いいな。ダイヤ、ダイヤ嘘ついて盗むようなやつだったんだ。
Wow, that's pretty good.
"The kind of person who lies and steals diamonds."
違うの、いやこんなね、団長にもこうやってさ、
No, I mean even to me, she's...
そう、物怖じせず絡んできてくれたり、もう本当に可愛いの。
...not afraid to interact with me, she's really cute.
じゃあノエルままだったら何でも許してくれる？
Then Noel-mama will forgive me for anything?
いやもう許しちゃう。
Oh, I'd forgive you.
ダメだよ！ダイヤ嘘ついて盗むのは！
You can't! Stealing diamonds with a lie!
いい子いい子。だから今ではね、どんどん後ろ行くのやめて？
Good girl, good girl. So now... wait, stop backing away!
今ではね、本当にいい子ですよ。
Now, she's a really good girl.
いい子でーす！頑張り屋さんでーす！イエーイ！
I'm a good girl! I'm a hard worker! Yay!
はい、でも本当におめでとうね、誕生日。おめでとう！
Yes, but really, happy birthday. Congratulations!
来てくれてありがとうございました。一緒に歌えて本当に嬉しかったです。
Thank you for coming.
I was really happy to sing with you.
スバルたちも嬉しかったぞ！
We were happy too!
え、何そのいちゃいちゃしてるの。
Eh, what's with all that flirting?
さぁはい、奏ちゃん、次、次、次があるからね！
Alright, Kanade-chan, next, there's more to come!
次があるからね。
There's a next part.
めっちゃ台本読むやん！
You're reading the script so intensely!
お前だよ！どっからどう考えても！
It's you! No matter how you look at it!
ちゃんと読みます、ちゃんと読んで。えー、スバルまま、ノエルまま、ありがとうございました！
I'll read it properly, read it properly.
Uh, Subaru-mama, Noel-mama, thank you!
なんと奏が、生パフォーマンスで一人で頑張るのみに...
Actually, Kanade is going to perform live all by herself...
...曲振りさせてもらってもいいですか！？
...so can I introduce the song!?
いいよー！やってー！
Sure! Go ahead!
次の曲は！
The next song is!
Beautiful!
Beautiful
作詞：越智志帆
作曲：蔦谷好位置 / 越智志帆
Beautiful
Lyrics: Shiho Ochi
Composition: Koichi Tsutaya / Shiho Ochi
遠くに伸びる影 夜の波が消した
A shadow stretching far away, erased by the waves of the night.
涙を流したなんて 気付かれないまま
Without anyone noticing that I was shedding tears.
心を捨てるなら 傷つく方がマシさ
If I'm to throw my heart away, it's better to get hurt.
冷たい風を切って 逃げるように走る
Cutting through the cold wind, running as if to escape.
いつかこの静寂は 宝石になるのでしょう
Someday this silence will surely become a jewel.
美しい心に 生まれ変わる そう信じて
Reborn into a beautiful heart, so I believe.
世界で一つの 輝く光になれ
Become the one and only shining light in the world.
私でいい 私を信じて行くのさ
It's okay to be me, I'll go on believing in myself.
今を舞え
Dance in the present.
Beautiful
見上げても どん詰まりで 君道をゆけ
Even if you look up and see a dead end, go your own way
私でいい
I'm fine as I am
私の歩幅で 生きていくのさ
I'll live at my own pace
誰かとを比べるのは 避けられない心情
Comparing yourself to others is an unavoidable feeling
誰かとを許すのは 難しい心情
Forgiving someone is a difficult feeling
ないもの探せば 数え切れないけれど
If I look for what I don't have, they are countless
ゆっくり愛してみよう 私というこの命を
Let's try to love slowly, this life called me
世界で一つの 輝く光になれ
Become the one and only shining light in the world
明かりのない 明日を迎えたとしても
Even if I face a tomorrow without light
悲しみの先に 孤独が押し寄せても
Even if loneliness rushes in beyond sadness
息をしている 今日も息をして生きている
I'm breathing; today, too, I'm breathing and living
世界で一つの
The one and only
私に幸あれ
May I be blessed
涙に幸あれ
May tears be blessed
明日に幸あれ
May tomorrow be blessed
世界で一つの 輝く光になれ
Become the one and only shining light in the world
泣いてもいい 私を歩いてゆくのさ
It's okay to cry; I will walk as myself
涙は頬 流れる星のようさ
Tears are like shooting stars flowing down my cheeks
私になれ 私を叶えて生きていくのさ
Become me; fulfill myself and live on
いつの日も...
Always...
はい！ということで
Yes! So,
いかがでしたでしょうか。
how was that?
ちょっとお水だけ飲んできます！
I'm just going to go drink some water!
さぁ、この響き曲の余韻が消えぬ間に、
Now, while the resonance of this song still lingers,
最後の曲聴いてください。
please listen to the last song.
GREATEST！
GREATEST!
目を開けて 口ずさむ 輝ける
Open your eyes, hum along, you can shine
きっと無敵になる
You'll surely become invincible
Feel my heart
GREATEST
See me become the GREATEST
No one can beat me
Cuz I'm a GREATEST
固く結び直した靴紐が 羽に見えて
The shoelaces I retied tightly look like wings
どこまででも飛べる 予感がする
I have a feeling I can fly anywhere
追いかけるなんて 趣味じゃない
Chasing isn't my style
追い越そう 明日だって
Let's overtake, even tomorrow
夢のまま終わるほど 眠くないわ
I'm not sleepy enough to let it end as a dream
そう 何もかも大丈夫
Right, everything's gonna be okay
奇跡よりも大胆に勝つの
Winning even more boldly than a miracle
見たことない景色だって
Even sights never seen before
光に満ちていく
Are filling with light
Wanna be the GREATEST
地図ならばこの胸に
If I need a map, it's in my heart
迸る熱がある
The heat is surging
誰も止めらんない My way
No one can stop me, My way
Wanna be the GREATEST
弱音も重ねればシンフォニー
Even my weaknesses, when layered, become a symphony
強くなれる
I can become stronger
歌って
So sing
きっと無敵になる
Surely I'll become invincible
(Feel my light)
部屋で一人描いたステージも
The stage I envisioned all alone in my room
覚えていて 居場所になる
Remember it, it'll become a home
声が聞こえてくる
I can hear your voices
深呼吸をして 飛び乗るくらいが正攻法だって
Take a deep breath, just jumping in is the right way to go
胸を張って踊るのも悪くないわ
Dancing with head held high isn't so bad either
恐れないで 大丈夫
Don't be afraid, it's okay
唱えるたび絶対になるの
Every time I chant it, it becomes absolute
一度きりの人生だって
Even with only one life
この手で舵を執れ
Take the wheel with these hands
Wanna be the GREATEST
私が私として
As myself
輝ける道を行く
Walking the path where I can shine
声も煌めいて My day
Even my voice sparkles, My day
Wanna be the GREATEST
目覚めを奏でてオーバーチュア
Playing the awakening, an overture
望むほどに叶って
It comes true as much as I wish
もっと素敵になる
Becoming even more wonderful
(Feel my light)
(Feel my heart)
(See me become the GREATEST)
(No one can beat me)
(Cuz I'm a GREATEST)
Wanna be the GREATEST
諦めた好きの数
The number of things I loved and gave up on
上を向く理由がある
There's a reason to look up
涙導いて My beat
Tears leading my beat
Wanna be the GREATEST
傷跡も連れてアレグロ
Bringing my scars along, allegro
強くなれる 歌って
I can become stronger, so sing
もっと光差す方へ
Towards where more light shines
きっと無敵になる
Surely I'll become invincible
(Feel my light)
（激しい息遣い）
(heavy breathing)
はぁ～い！ということで
Alright! So...
今、聞いていたのが…あっ、聞いていただいていたのが
The song you were just listening to... I mean, that you were listening to...
もう完全に力がなくなってしまいました。安心して
My energy is completely gone now. Relieved,
今、聞いていただいたのが、なんと！奏の初オリ曲！
the song you just listened to was, believe it or not, Kanade's first original song!
『GREATEST』です！
It's titled 'GREATEST'!
すごい！ジャケットが！
Wow! The cover art!
作詞作曲は七穂（管弦楽団）さん…噛んじゃった、管弦楽団さんです！
The music and lyrics are by Nanaho (Kangen Gakudan)... I stumbled, Kangen Gakudan!
こちらの楽曲は、そうですね、どういう楽曲か…
As for what kind of song this is...
すごい…言うと、ガッと…簡単に言うと
It's really... putting it simply...
え～、韓国から夢を叶えに来た音乃瀬奏なりの
It's like a 'glittery, shiny' song
ギラギラソング、キラキラソングみたいな感じとなっていて
fitting for Otonose Kanade, who came from Korea to make her dreams come true.
奏がこういうのを信じてやっていきたいんだみたいなのを伝えて
I shared how I wanted to believe in things like this and keep going,
書いていただきました。すごい、なんて素敵な歌詞を
and they wrote it for me. Such wonderful lyrics,
本当に素敵な楽曲と歌詞、ありがとうございます！
and such a wonderful song. Thank you so much!
めちゃ気に入ってます！そして、4月21日0時から
I love it! Also, starting at midnight on April 21st,
この後おそらく3時…あっ、3時間後に楽曲リリースもされます！
which is probably in... about three hours, the song will be released!
イエーイ！パチパチ～！ありがと～！
Yay! *Clap clap*! Thank you!
最高すぎたわ、ありがと～！MVはね、ちょっと後日公開なんですけれども
That was the best, thank you! The MV will be released at a later date,
ぜひ公開されたら、いっぱい見てください！はい！
so please watch it a lot when it's out! Okay!
新曲の披露もできたところで、告知タイムです！
Now that I've performed the new song, it's time for announcements!
まず1つ目は、皆さんお待ちかね、グッズの紹介です！
First up is something you've all been waiting for: the merch reveal!
こちら！音乃瀬奏 誕生日記念2025！
Here it is! Otonose Kanade Birthday Celebration 2025!
フルセットはこんな感じになってます。可愛い～！
This is what the full set looks like. So cute!
可愛いだろ？可愛いだろ？ちょっとコメントにラグがあって拾いづらいんだけど
Isn't it cute? Isn't it? There's a bit of lag in the comments, so it's hard to catch them...
『うぉ～！おめでとう！最高だったよオリ曲！』まだオリ曲の下りか
'Whoa! Congratulations! The original song was awesome!' Ah, still on the original song.
今回のキービジュアルはごんじママに描いていただきました。可愛いでしょ～！
The key visual this time was drawn by Gonji-mama. Isn't it cute!
ま、でもオリ曲はね、
Well, about the original song,
みんなすごい念願のオリ曲みたいな感じだったから、
it seemed like everyone was really looking forward to it,
いっぱい喜んでもらえて嬉しいです！
so I'm glad I could make you happy!
それではグッズ一つずつ見ていきましょう！
Now, let's take a look at the merchandise one by one!
一つ目！
First up!
ワイドラバーマット！
The Wide Rubber Mat!
キービジュアルのオリジナルパジャマを着た奏のキュートなデザインのラバーマットです！
It's a rubber mat with a cute design of Kanade in her original pajamas from the key visual!
キーボードとマウスを乗せて使えるワイドサイズになっています。
It's a wide size that can fit a keyboard and mouse.
二つ目はこちら！
The second one is this!
奏が落書きしちゃったW Tシャツです！
The "Kanade Scribbled All Over It" W T-shirt!
あの、実際に奏がね、描き下ろしデザインのTシャツです！描きました！
Um, it's a T-shirt with a design actually drawn by Kanade! I drew it!
よかったら奏と一緒にTシャツ一枚持ってる民になってくれませんか？
If you'd like, won't you join the ranks of those who own a T-shirt just like mine?
いっぱい買ってください！
Please buy lots of them!
そして三つ目！
And the third one!
タンブラーです！
It's a tumbler!
衣装のね、こちらのリボンをモチーフにした日常使いができる落ち着いたデザイン。
It features the ribbon from my outfit as a motif, with a calm design suitable for daily use.
会社などで使って是非とも奏を宣伝してください！
Please use it at work or elsewhere to help promote Kanade!
そして次はこちら！
And next is this!
奏のぷにぷにクッション！
Kanade's Squishy Cushion!
ま、いっか、寝ている表情のフェイスクッションです！
Well, whatever, it's a face cushion with a sleeping expression!
特別に奏のほっぺをぷにぷにしてよしと台本に書かれていますが...
It says in the script that you're allowed to squish Kanade's cheeks as a special treat...
許可した覚えはありません！
but I don't recall giving permission for that!
ぷにぷにじゃない奏な！はい！
I'm not squishy! Okay!
そしてフルセット購入特典はこちら！
And here are the full set purchase bonuses!
フルセット購入、直筆サイン＆箔押し複製メッセージ入りポストカード！
Full set purchase bonus: a postcard with a handwritten signature and a foil-pressed reproduced message!
今回数量限定ではないので、フルセット買ってくれた方全員に直筆サインが届きます！
This time it's not limited in quantity, so everyone who buys the full set will receive a handwritten signature!
みんな安心してね！戦争じゃないからゆっくり買ってもいいぞ！
Don't worry, everyone! It's not a war, so you can take your time buying!
奏も腱鞘炎になりながら書くからね！
Kanade will be writing them until she gets tendonitis!
うわー頑張って書くぞー！
Whoa, I'll do my best to write them all!
今回は誕生日記念2025お礼ボイスも付きます！
This time, it also comes with a "Birthday Celebration 2025 Thank-You Voice"!
さらに、フルセット特典として昨年の9月から発売されたhololive OFFICIAL CARD GAMEで使用できるカードが1枚付きます！
Furthermore, as a full set bonus, you'll get one card that can be used in the hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME, which has been on sale since last September!
カードはhololive production OFFICIAL SHOPで購入された方のみ対象となりますが、可愛い！
The card is only for those who purchase from the hololive production OFFICIAL SHOP, but it's so cute!
特典につくのは推しアピールできるPカード、推しホロメンカードです！
The bonus card is a "P" (Producer) card, a "Support" card to show off your favorite!
カードの詳細や遊び方については、ホームページにてご確認ください。
Please check the official website for card details and how to play.
カードは日本語版のみとなりますのでご了承ください。
Please note that the cards are only available in Japanese.
以上グッズ紹介でした！
That's all for the merchandise introduction!
そして告知二つ目はこちら！
And the second announcement is this!
なんと！LINEスタンプ制作決定！！！
Tada! A LINE stamp production has been decided!!!
すごーい！可愛いでしょ？すまそーって！
Amazing! Isn't it cute? "Sorry!"
すまそーってやってる！パチパチありがとう！
"Sorry!" It's doing that! Thank you for the applause!
えっと...発売日はまだ未定ですが、こんな感じの可愛いイラストのスタンプです！
Um... the release date is still undecided, but it'll be stamps with cute illustrations like these!
セリフとかも奏が考えて作ってもらっているので、乞うご期待！
I'm also thinking of the dialogue for them, so stay tuned!
詳細は後日また告知をします。お楽しみに！
More details will be announced at a later date. Please look forward to it!
以上告知でした！
That's all for the announcements!
ということで、音乃瀬奏生誕祭2025、あ、違うこちら...毎回間違える、2025！
And so, Otonose Kanade's Birthday Celebration 2025—oh wait, this way... I always make that mistake, 2025!
はい、いかがでしたでしょうか？初めてのアコギの挑戦だったり...
Yes, how did you like it? My first time challenging the acoustic guitar...
「すごいかっこいい」ってコメントしてくれてたの見たよ！嬉しかったし、
I saw the comments saying "It was so cool"! I was so happy,
すごい頑張って準備したので、あのいっぱい見ていただけて嬉しい限りです！
and I worked really hard preparing for it, so I'm just so glad so many of you watched it!
本当に嬉しいよ、オリ曲も公開できて。
I'm really happy, also because I could release my original song.
あの、リリースされたらいっぱい聴いてね！
Please listen to it a lot when it's out!
すごいまだコメント欄がぷにぷにのくだりになってる。
The comment section is still stuck on the "squishy" thing.
おせーんだよ、予測して打て！拾えねーだろ！
You guys are slow, you should've predicted it and started typing! I can't keep up!
えーということで、えー、この後のスケジュールをちょっとざっくり皆さんにお教えしますと、
Anyway, um, let me give you a quick rundown of the upcoming schedule:
21時10分からグッズ販売開始を行います！
merchandise sales will start at 21:10!
そして21時20分から、あ、こちら、20分から
And at 21:20—oh, this way—from 21:20,
メンバーシップ限定のアンコールライブ、アンコールライブもありますので、そちらもよろしくお願いします！
there will also be a member-only encore live, an encore live, so please look forward to that too!
今がメン限入り時だよみんな、今今、今入りな！はい！
Now is the best time to join the membership, everyone, now, now, join now! Okay!
そして...多分もう終わりかな？忘れてることないよね？はい！
And... I guess that's all? I haven't forgotten anything, right? Okay!
ということで、じゃあ、おつかなででしたー！来てくれてありがとうー！イェーイ！
And so, then, "Otsukanade"! Thank you for coming! Yay!
あ待って待って待って待って！待って待って待って待って！待って待って！
Wait, wait, wait, wait! Wait, wait, wait, wait! Wait, wait!
一個大事なのを忘れてた！一番大事なお知らせ！
I forgot one important thing! The most important announcement!
はい、告知！それでは皆さん聞いてください。
Yes, an announcement! Now everyone, please listen.
奏からの、もうオリ曲並みに大事なお知らせ！
An announcement from Kanade that's just as important as the original song!
デレーン！あしたは月曜日！
Tada! Tomorrow is Monday!
月曜日！月曜日！ルンルンルン...
Monday! Monday! Runrunrun...
みんな夢から覚める時間だよ...もう夢から覚める時間だよ...
It's time for everyone to wake up from their dream... It's already time to wake up from the dream...
奏の生誕ライブが、アンコールライブが終わったらもう終わりだよー！イェーイ！
Once Kanade's birthday live and the encore live are over, it's all over! Yay!
見てくれてありがとう！
やっと夢に向けて一歩踏み出せました！
Thank you for watching!
I finally took a step toward my dream!
私はもっともっと輝きたい！
奏の歌を届けていきたい！
I want to shine more and more!
I want to deliver Kanade's songs!
もっと素敵な景色を見せられるように
がんばります！1周年！
I'll do my best to show you even more wonderful
sights! 1st Anniversary!